<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 | Elias Storms</title>
    <link>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication-type/2/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication-type/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>2</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2023 Elias Storms</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.eliasstorms.net/media/icon_hu30740375d135df8f89c11012417564b7_13611_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication-type/2/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Transparency is Meant for Control&#39; and Vice Versa: Learning from Co-designing and Evaluating Algorithmic News Recommenders</title>
      <link>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2022b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2022b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Publication for CSCW 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algorithmic systems that recommend content often lack transparency
about how they come to their suggestions. One area in which
recommender systems are increasingly prevalent is online news
distribution. In this paper, we explore how a lack of transparency of
(news) recommenders can be tackled by involving users in the design of
interface elements. In the context of automated decision-making,
legislative frameworks such as the GDPR in Europe introduce a specific
conception of transparency, granting &amp;lsquo;data subjects&amp;rsquo; specific rights
and imposing obligations on service providers. An important related
question is how people using personalized recommender systems relate
to the issue of transparency, not as legal data subjects but as users.
This paper builds upon a two-phase study on how users conceive of
transparency and related issues in the context of algorithmic news
recommenders. We organized co-design workshops to elicit participants&amp;rsquo;
&amp;lsquo;algorithmic imaginaries&amp;rsquo; and invited them to ideate interface
elements for increased transparency. This revealed the importance of
combining legible transparency features with features that increase
user control. We then conducted a qualitative evaluation of mock-up
prototypes to investigate users&amp;rsquo; preferences and concerns when dealing
with design features to increase transparency and control. Our
investigation illustrates how users&amp;rsquo; expectations and impressions of
news recommenders are closely related to their news reading practices.
On a broader level, we show how transparency and control are
conceptually intertwined. Transparency without control leaves users
frustrated. Conversely, without a basic level of transparency into how
a system works, users remain unsure of the impact of controls.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time regimes in debt collection and mediation</title>
      <link>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The full article is included in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eliasstorms.net/schuld-in-meervoud&#34;&gt;doctoral dissertation.&lt;/a&gt;
While the other parts are in Dutch, you can read the original article in chapter 11 in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eliasstorms.net/schuld-in-meervoud/storms-2020-schuld-in-meervoud.pdf&#34;&gt;the PDF version.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debt and time are inherently linked. In its essence, a debt is a quantified promise to pay at some point in the future. This article explores the temporal dimension of debt that manifests itself during the process of debt collection, the phase at which indebtedness becomes most tangible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on in-depth interviews and ethnographic fieldwork in the world of debt collection in Flanders, Belgium, we analyse how different temporal techniques used by &amp;lsquo;street-level&amp;rsquo; debt collectors incite debtors to pay. Both in collection out of court by collection agencies as well as in judicial enforcement of the obligation to pay, debt collection imposes a strict schedule of repayment on the defaulting debtor. In this &amp;rsquo;time regime&amp;rsquo; imposed upon debtors, payments are closely tracked, so that any deviation can be met by swift reminders and pecuniary punishment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time regimes of debt collection can conflict with the temporal structures present in the everyday economic lives of the debtors. Incongruences appear due to frictions between the rhythm of repayment on the one hand, and temporal irregularities of the economic lives of debtors on the other. To further explore this time dimension, we also look at how debtors respond and adapt to the new temporal impositions, and how debt mediators deploy temporal strategies when assisting the over-indebted. By negotiating payment plans with creditors, debt mediators mitigate the harsher aspects of the time regime enacted through collection agencies and judicial officers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
