<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications | Elias Storms</title>
    <link>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Publications</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 Elias Storms</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.eliasstorms.net/media/icon_hu30740375d135df8f89c11012417564b7_13611_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schuldinvordering en de schuldenspiraal. Hoe het &#39;doen betalen&#39; van achterstallen schuldproblemen verergert</title>
      <link>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving the Debate: Interface elements that enhance civility and relevance in online news comments</title>
      <link>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/bossens-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/bossens-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foregrounding Algorithms: Preparing Users for Co-design with Sensitizing Activities</title>
      <link>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/alvarado-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/alvarado-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Paper presented at the NordiCHI 2020 conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algorithms are present in many of our everyday activities.
However, there is generally low awareness of their presence among users, and there are various conceptualizations to define them.
Additionally, algorithms are often both complex and opaque.
These characteristics raise challenges when applying co-design activities to the interaction design of algorithms.
We argue that researchers can overcome these challenges by developing sensitizing activities: activities that foreground the presence of algorithms, thus raising algorithmic awareness and a shared understanding, without influencing their initial experiences and expectations.
We share how we applied sensitizing activities in two case studies: sensitizing interviews, and diary studies together with two-phase workshops.
We share our experiences applying these techniques to overcome the challenges of low algorithmic awareness and multiple algorithmic understandings of participants.
Finally, we offer recommendations for researchers and practitioners when applying sensitizing activities in this design context and invite further methodological discussion on this challenging topic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schuld in meervoud. Een sociologische verkenning van schuldinvordering tussen economie, recht en sociaal werk</title>
      <link>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Doctoraal proefschrift verdedigd in januari 2020.
Meer informatie en het volledige manuscript zijn &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eliasstorms.net/schuld-in-meervoud&#34;&gt;hier beschikbaar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Actor-Network Theory in the Investigation of Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2019b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2019b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Paper accepted for the workshop
&lt;a href=&#34;https://authentic.sice.indiana.edu/philosophy-hci-workshop/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Standing on the Shoulders of Giants: Exploring the Intersection of Philosophy and HCI&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;
at the CHI 2019 conference in Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This draft connects &lt;em&gt;Actor-Network Theory&lt;/em&gt; and Human-Computer Interaction, reflecting on ongoing research on algorithmic ranking and selection.
It is very much a &lt;em&gt;working paper&lt;/em&gt;, and even though work on it has stalled, I am still interested in turning it into a full article at some point in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This short paper, a submission for the HCI workshop &amp;lsquo;Standing on the Shoulders of Giants&amp;rsquo;, looks at scholarly studies of the presence of algorithmic selection in everyday life and how existing research benefits from and is connected to Actor-Network Theory (ANT). The paper then suggests that the empirical and philosophical strengths of ANT could benefit not just algorithms, but the broader field of HCI. With this exercise, this submission touches upon multiple key topics of the workshop. Most prominently, the paper addresses topics 2 and 6 by suggesting how ANT could connect to existing debates on, for example, &amp;lsquo;post-userism&amp;rsquo;. Also topic 5 is relevant, since the rather obscure philosophical underpinnings of ANT need to be made more accessible if we hope to make its approach useful for HCI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time regimes in debt collection and mediation</title>
      <link>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The full article is included in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eliasstorms.net/schuld-in-meervoud&#34;&gt;doctoral dissertation.&lt;/a&gt;
While the other parts are in Dutch, you can read the original article in chapter 11 in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eliasstorms.net/schuld-in-meervoud/storms-2020-schuld-in-meervoud.pdf&#34;&gt;the PDF version.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debt and time are inherently linked. In its essence, a debt is a quantified promise to pay at some point in the future. This article explores the temporal dimension of debt that manifests itself during the process of debt collection, the phase at which indebtedness becomes most tangible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on in-depth interviews and ethnographic fieldwork in the world of debt collection in Flanders, Belgium, we analyse how different temporal techniques used by &amp;lsquo;street-level&amp;rsquo; debt collectors incite debtors to pay. Both in collection out of court by collection agencies as well as in judicial enforcement of the obligation to pay, debt collection imposes a strict schedule of repayment on the defaulting debtor. In this &amp;rsquo;time regime&amp;rsquo; imposed upon debtors, payments are closely tracked, so that any deviation can be met by swift reminders and pecuniary punishment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time regimes of debt collection can conflict with the temporal structures present in the everyday economic lives of the debtors. Incongruences appear due to frictions between the rhythm of repayment on the one hand, and temporal irregularities of the economic lives of debtors on the other. To further explore this time dimension, we also look at how debtors respond and adapt to the new temporal impositions, and how debt mediators deploy temporal strategies when assisting the over-indebted. By negotiating payment plans with creditors, debt mediators mitigate the harsher aspects of the time regime enacted through collection agencies and judicial officers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanningen en uitdagingen na 20 jaar Collectieve Schuldenregeling</title>
      <link>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boekbespreking: Graeber (2015), The Utopia of Rules</title>
      <link>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schuldenoverlast in Vlaanderen. Dimensies van de schuldenproblematiek nader bekeken</title>
      <link>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krediet, schulden en betalingsproblemen. Een verkenning van schuldenoverlast als sociaal probleem aan de hand van actueel onderzoek</title>
      <link>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2014b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.eliasstorms.net/publication/storms-2014b/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
